Fitchburg, Mass. Calvinistic Congregational Church records, 1805-2006.
Congregational Library & Archives
Fitchburg, Mass. Calvinistic Congregational Church records, 1805-2006.
RG5368
Congregational Library & Archives
11.16 Cubic Feet
(23 boxes)
The Calvinistic Congregational Church of Fitchburg, Massachusetts, was formally gathered as the Calvinistic Congregational Society on June 14, 1805. The first meeting house was built in 1806, the second in 1845, and the third, now listed on the National Register of Historic Places, in 1897. The church joined the United Church of Christ in 1961. In 1967, the church joined with the First Methodist Church of Fitchburg to form the Faith United Parish. This collection documents the history and activities of the parish and its members. The records contain committee reports, meeting minutes, vital statistics, financial records, photographic materials, weekly church bulletins, and extensive records kept by various church societies.
Calvinistic Congregational Church (Fitchburg, Mass.)
Rollstone Congregational Church (Fitchburg, Mass.)
Sabbath School Society of Fitchburg. Library
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were gifted to the Congregational Library & Archives, March 2018, by Rev. Jeffrey Conlon; Accession 2018-08.
Historical Note
The Calvinistic Congregational Church of Fitchburg, Massachusetts, was formally gathered as the Calvinistic Congregational Society on June 14, 1805. The church formed during a period of religious tumult within the town of Fitchburg, and within New England in general. Doctrinal disagreements within the First Parish of Fitchburg between Unitarian and Trinitarian congregants came to a head in 1802 with the majority of the more traditionally minded congregants withdrawing from the First Parish. Those that withdrew did so with the intention to form a new religious society. They formed as the Calvinistic Congregational Church three years later. The first meeting house of the Calvinistic Congregational Church was built in 1806 at the corner of Main Street and Rollstone Street. That meeting house was replaced in 1845. The second meeting house was built to accommodate a growing parish; eventually the building was adjoined with a chapel. In 1897, the third and final meeting house was built on the same plot of land. Designed by Henry M. Francis, the third church building is an example of Richardsonian Romanesque architecture and was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1979. The meeting house's most prominent features were a clock tower and the 20 foot diameter "rose window," which was a stained glass window depicting the angelic choir.
The same kinds of doctrinal disagreements that had resulted in the formation of the Calvinistic Congregational Church from the First Parish of Fitchburg resulted in the formation of a number of other protestant denominations from the Calvinistic Church during the nineteenth-century. The Methodist, Episcopal, and Baptists churches of Fitchburg formed from doctrinal splits within the Calvinistic Church. The Trinitarian Congregational Church split from the Calvinistic Church in 1843 following three tumultuous years of discussions about slavery; its members withdrew from the Calvinistic Church shortly before the Calvinistic Church formally adopted a resolution condemning slavery as an "evil of great magnitude." By 1867 the population in eastern portion of Fitchburg had grown significantly and those members wished to worship in a church more convenient to them; in 1868 those members formed the Rollstone Congregational Church. The Trinitarian Church eventually merged with the Rollstone Congregational Church around 1870.
In 1961, the Calvinistic Congregational Church voted to join with the United Church of Christ. Beginning in 1966, the Calvinistic Church reached out to the other parishes that had formed from it to begin talks of creating a "cooperative parish." The First Methodist Church responded, and in 1967 the Faith United Parish was formed by the two churches. Both churches continued to hold separate finances, polity, and membership, but held joint worship and shared programs and clubs. Both churches stayed united until 2018 when both churches, and Faith United Parish, were formally dissolved.
Scope and Contents
The Fitchburg, Mass. Calvinistic Congregational Church records document the history and activities of parish and its members. This collection contains church and society records, including committee reports, meeting minutes, vital membership records, and church correspondence. Also included are financial records, photographic materials, weekly church bulletins, event calendars, and extensive records kept by various church societies and clubs, including the records of the Fitchburg Sunday School.
Arrangement
This collection has been divided into five series, with two of those series further divided into subseries. Materials have been arranged in chronological order. Materials closely related by topic have been grouped together when appropriate. When possible, the original order of materials within folders has been maintained.
Series 1: Church and committee records, 1805-2006.
Subseries 1: Church and society records, 1805-1983.
Subseries 2: Vital records, 1824-2006.
Subseries 3: Committee reports and minutes, 1859-1973.
Subseries 4: Church history, 1868-1968.
Subseries 5: Annual reports, 1882-1990.
Subseries 6: Correspondence and communications, 1906-1959.
Series 2: Financial records, 1824-1998.
Series 3: Church societies and clubs, 1825-1995.
Subseries 1: Sunday School Society of Fitchburg, 1825-1976.
Subseries 2: Sewing Society, 1839-1859.
Subseries 3: Young People's Society, 1886-1930.
Subseries 4: Fitchburg Congregational Club, 1888.
Subseries 5: Kings Daughters of the C. C. Church, 1888-1967.
Subseries 6: United Workers of the C. C. Church, 1891-1957.
Subseries 7: Fraternal Brotherhood of the C. C. Church, 1910-1942.
Subseries 8: Fitchburg Choral Society, 1911-1930.
Subseries 9: Fitchburg Woman's Club, 1919-1945.
Subseries 10: Hisanhern Club of the C. C. Church, 1941-1995.
Subseries 11: Woman's Guild of the C. C. Church, 1953-1970.
Subseries 12: Aims, Ambitions, Ideals Service Club of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1953-1970.
Subseries 13: Junior Pilgrim youth Fellowship, 1954-1966.
Subseries 14: COMETS, 1976-1995.
Series 4: Calendars and bulletins, 1887-1972.
Series 5: Graphic materials, circa 1914-1980.
Related Materials
Materials from the First Methodist Church of Fitchburg, Mass. were gifted to the School of Theology Library at Boston University in 2018.
Bibliography
Committee on Archives. 200 Years. Fitchburg, 1968.17.11.1 F55.3 FaiUP
Hitchcock, George A. A History of the Calvinistic Congregational Church and Society. Fitchburg, 1902. 17.11.1 F55.3 CalCC
Antislavery movements.; Baptismal records.; Church bulletins.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church music -- Societies, etc.; Church records and registers.; Church societies.; Marriage records.; Pews and pew rights.; Sunday schools.; Sunday schools -- Records.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Worship programs.; Atlanta University -- Records and correspondence.; Calvinistic Congregational Church (Fitchburg, Mass.); Faith United Parish (Fitchburg, Mass.); First Church in Fitchburg (Fitchburg, Mass.); First Methodist Episcopal Church (Fitchburg, Mass.); Fitchburg (Mass.) -- Church history.; Hampton Normal Agricultural Institute (Va.) -- Records and correspondence.; Rollstone Congregational Church (Fitchburg, Mass.); Sabbath School Society of Fitchburg. Library; Washburn College -- Records and correspondence.
- Church and committee records, 1805 2006; 1805-2006; 81 Files; (17 volumes, 64 folders)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the official records of the Calvinistic Congregational Church and Society. Included in the records are church registers and ledgers, meeting minutes and committee reports, vital statistics, membership lists, church correspondence, and documents related to the church's history and anniversary celebrations.
  - Church and society records, 1805 1983; 1805-1983; 30 Files; (10 volumes, 20 folders)
    This subseries contains the official records of the Calvinistic Church and Society. Primarily the series contains record books and ledgers which include meeting minutes, record of votes, and other official church documents, such as copies of the church constitution and by-laws. Also included with the church record books are supplementary church records, such as officer retreat and clerk records, records and floor plans of the 1954 renovation, year book reports, and various iterations of church handbooks.
    - Church records vol. 1, 1805 1835; 1805-1835 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Church records vol. 2, 1835 1845; 1835-1845 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Church records vol. 3, 1845 1871; 1845-1871 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Church records vol. 4, 1871 1889; 1871-1889 (Box 1, Volume 4)
    - Church records, 1871 1889; 1871-1889 (Box 1, Volume 5)
    - Church records vol. 6, 1916 1922; 1916-1922 (Box 1, Volume 6)
    - Church records, 1922 1928; 1922-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Church records, 1929 1942; 1929-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Church records, 1954 1965; 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Church records, 1966 1977; 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Calvinistic Congregational Society records, 1805 1844; 1805-1844 (Box 1, Volume 7)
    - Calvinistic Congregational Society records, 1843 1902; 1843-1902 (Box 7, Volume 2)
    - Calvinistic Congregational Society records, 1882 1922; 1882-1922 (Box 1, Volume 8)
    - Calvinistic Congregational Society records, 1903 1922; 1903-1922 (Box 7, Volume 3)
    - Calvinistic Congregational Society records, 1920 1922; 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Church handbooks, 1878 1960; 1878-1960 (Box 18)
    - Dedication service, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous "Important" records, 1922 1948; 1922-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Pastor's report, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Year book reports, 1924 1945; 1924-1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Record of votes on the UCC merger, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Church renovations, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Church renovations floor plan, 1954 (Folder 2, Item 1)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Officers retreat, 1958 1960; 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pilgrim Press, 1959 1962; 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Albion Down memorial, 1960 1969; 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Records of the clerk, 1967 1983; 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Church status reports and minister search, 1976 1978; 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Recordings, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Vital records, 1824 2006; 1824-2006; 20 Files; (4 volumes, 16 folders)
    This subseries contains the vital records of the Calvinistic Congregational Church. Included are birth records, marriage records, records of deaths, baptismal records, admissions, dismissions, and membership lists.
    - Register of communicants, 1824 1900; 1824-1900 (Box 5, Volume 7)
    - Members list, 1828 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - New members, 1866 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Dismissions, 1881 1911; 1881-1911 (Box 5, Volume 10)
    - Dismissions, 1937 1940; 1937-1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Dismissions, 1949 1968; 1949-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Membership and dues, 1892 1898; 1892-1898 (Box 5, Volume 8)
    - Church directory, 1893 (Box 5, Volume 9)
    - Certificate of communion, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Member directory, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Baptisms, 1928 1957; 1928-1957 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Baptisms, 1957 1966; 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Weddings, 1928 1957; 1928-1957 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Weddings, 1957 1966; 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Funerals, 1928 1957; 1928-1957 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Funerals, 1957 1966; 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Membership, 1928 1957; 1928-1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Membership and Dr. Hugh Penny vital records, 1957 1967; 1957-1967 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Certificates of church membership, 1957 1968; 1957-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Membership and vital records, 1994 2006; 1994-2006 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Committee reports and minutes, 1859 1973; 1859-1973; 14 Files; (2 volumes, 12 folders)
    This subseries contains the minutes, reports, and records of the various church committees that were involved in the governance and management of the Calvinistic Congregational Church.
    - Standing Committee records, 1859 1922; 1859-1922 (Box 1, Volume 9)
    - Standing Committee records, 1904 1918; 1904-1918 (Box 1, Volume 10)
    - Standing Committee records, 1917 1919; 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Standing Committee minutes, 1919 1921; 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Church Committee records, 1922 1938; 1922-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Church Committee records, 1926 1948; 1926, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Church Committee records, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Church Committee records, 1948 1954; 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Church Committee records, 1954 1965; 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Committee of 25, 1952 1959; 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Board of Deacons minutes, 1957 1963; 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bi-Centennial Committee, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Psrish Council minutes, 1967 1970; 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Parish Council minutes, 1971 1973; 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Church history, 1868 1968; 1868-1968; 5 Files; (1 volume, 4 folders)
    This subseries contains records related to the history of the church and the publications produced during church anniversaries.
    - A Centenary Discourse, 1868 (Box 18)
    - History of the Calvinistic Congregational Church of Fitchburg Mass, 1900 (Box 6, Volume 1)
    - Clippings, 1930 1960; circa 1930-1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Church history, 1954 1968; 1954-1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - 200 Years, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Annual reports, 1882 1990; 1882-1990; 6 Folders
    This subseries contains the annual reports produced and complied by the Calvinistic Congregational Church.
    - Annual Reports, 1882 1887; 1882-1887 (Box 18)
    - Reports of the annual meetings, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Annual reports, 1938 1946; 1938-1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1948 1961; 1948-1961 (Box 19)
    - Annual Reports, 1962 1975; 1962-1975 (Box 20)
    - Annual Reports, 1975 1990; 1975-1990 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence and communications, 1906 1959; 1906-1959; 7 Folders
    This subseries contains a record of the official communications and correspondence of the church. Included in this subseries are internal communication, such as committee correspondence, and external communications, such as correspondence with active and inactive church members. Also included are letters of resignation.
    - Miscellaneous church communications, 1906 1945; undated, 1906, 1931-1945 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Church correspondence, 1920 1949; 1920-1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Committee correspondence, 1935 1948; 1935-1948 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Resignations, 1936 1949; 1936-1949 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Membership communications, 1939 1940; 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Non-resident membership correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Inactive members correspondence, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Financial records, 1824 1998; 1824-1998; 35 Files; (13 volumes, 22 folders)
  This series contains the financial records of the Calvinistic Congregational Church. Included in the records are valuations, tax bills, receipts, the treasurer's ledgers, records of gifts and pledges, and pew deed books.
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society treasurer's book, 1824 1858; 1824-1858 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society book of orders, 1824 1870; 1824-1870 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - Tax bill, 1824 1842; 1824-1842 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Valuations, 1825 1829; 1825-1829 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Valuations, 1830 1844; 1830-1844 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Church treasurer's book, 1848 1923; 1848-1923 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Church account book, 1855 1961; 1855-1961 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Treasurer's settlements, 1866 1874; 1866-1874 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pew book, 1883 1891; 1883-1891 (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - Pew book, 1897 1905; 1897-1905 (Box 2, Volume 7)
  - Pew book, 1906 1908; 1906-1908 (Box 2, Volume 8)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society treasurer's book, 1883 1898; 1883-1898 (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1883 1884; 1883-1884 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1884 1885; 1884-1885 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1884 1885; 1884-1885 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1885 1886; 1885-1886 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1885 1886; 1885-1886 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1886 1887; 1886-1887 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1886 1887; 1886-1887 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1887 1888; 1887-1888 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Calvinistic Congregational Society receipts, 1888 1889; 1888-1889 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Parish treasurer's book, 1891 1895; 1891-1895 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Reports of value, 1922 1924; 1922-1924 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Insurance valuation and non-members list, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Church ledger, 1929 1944; 1929-1944 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Reciepts and disbursements, 1942 1968; 1942-1968 (Box 2, Volume 7)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1967 1970; 1967-1970 (Box 2, Volume 8)
  - Church check book, 1945 1949; 1945-1949 (Box 2, Volume 6)
  - Church gift presentation, circa 1960 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Church treasurer's record, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 22, Volume 1)
  - Church pledge book, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 2, Volume 6)
  - Sale of parsonage, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Unnamed gift, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Capital Campaing Fund correspondence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Church societies and clubs, 1825 1995; 1825-1995; 87 Files; (39 volumes, 48 folders)
  This series contains the records of various church societies, organizations, and clubs that run beneath the umbrella of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, and later the Faith United Parish. Especially prominent are the records of women's benevolent groups and the Sunday School Society of Fitchburg.
  - Sunday School Society of Fitchburg, 1825 1976; 1825-1976; 18 Files; (4 volumes, 14 folders)
    This subseries contains the records of the Sunday School Society. Included in the records are meeting minutes, annual reports, financial records, and correspondence with outside colleges.
    - Sunday School Society subscriptions, 1825 1828; 1825-1828 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Sunday School Society documents, 1825 1835; circa 1825-1835 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sunday School Society bills, 1826 1828; 1826-1828 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sunday School Society reports, 1829 1842; 1829-1842 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sunday School Society reports, 1843 1872; 1843-1872 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sunday School records, 1833 1895; 1833-1895 (Box 5, Volume 1)
    - Sunday School reports, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Superintendent's records, 1869 1871; 1869-1871 (Box 5, Volume 2)
    - Sunday School annual reports, 1876 1898; 1876-1898 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sunday School annual reports, 1895 1909; 1895-1909 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sunday School financial records, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sunday School records and correspondence, 1881 1898; 1881-1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hampton Normal Agricultural Institute correspondence, 1882 1889; 1882-1889 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Washburn College correspondence, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Atlanta University correspondence, 1898 1901; 1898-1901 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sunday School library catalogue, 1904 (Box 5, Volume 3)
    - Sunday School attendance records, 1955 1961; 1955-1961 (Box 5, Volume 4)
    - Sunday School records, 1957 1976; 1957-1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sewing Society, 1839 1859; 1839-1859; 2 Volumes
    This subseries contains the record books of the women's Sewing Society.
    - Sewing Society records, 1839 1848; 1839-1848 (Box 6, Volume 2)
    - Sewing Society records, 1849 1859; 1849-1859 (Box 6, Volume 3)
  - Young People's Society, 1886 1930; 1886-1930; 5 Volumes
    This subseries contains the records of the Young People's Society, including minutes, membership lists, and multiple versions of the constitution.
    - Young People's Society constitution records, 1886 1888; 1886-1888 (Box 4, Volume 8)
    - Young People's Society constituion, members, and committees, 1890 1895; 1890-1895 (Box 4, Volume 9)
    - Young People's Society constitution and members, 1917 (Box 4, Volume 10)
    - Young People's Society records, 1923-1930 (Box 4, Volume 11)
    - Young People's Society constitution and members, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Volume 12)
  - Fitchburg Congregational Club, 1888; 1 Volume
    This subseries contains the manual of the Fitchburg Congregational Club.
    - Congregational Club manual, 1888 (Box 5, Volume 6)
  - Kings Daughters of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1888 1967; 1888-1967; 23 Files; (14 volumes, 9 folders)
    This subseries contains the records of the Kings Daughters of the C. C. Church including record books, ledgers, the constitution, receipts, membership lists and due collections, and clippings. Also included are some materials from the Rollstone Congregational Church's branch of the King's Daughters.
    - King's Daughters secretary records, 1888 1899; 1888-1899 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    - King's Daughters records, 1899 1908; 1899-1908 (Box 3, Volume 2)
    - King's Daughters records, 1908 1915; 1908-1915 (Box 3, Volume 3)
    - King's Daughters records, 1915 1925; 1915-1925 (Box 3, Volume 4)
    - King's Daughters records, 1925 1936; 1925-1936 (Box 3, Volume 5)
    - King's Daughters records, 1936 1951; 1936-1951 (Box 3, Volume 6)
    - King's Daughters records, 1951 1963; 1951-1963 (Box 3, Volume 7)
    - King's Daughters constitutions, 1898 1963; 1898, 1951-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - King's Daughters clippings, 1915 1936; 1915-1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - King's Daughters programs and events, 1956 1967; 1956-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - King's Daughters ledger, 1898 1922; 1898-1922 (Box 3, Volume 8)
    - King's Daughters treasurer's records, 1922 1946; 1922-1946 (Box 3, Volume 9)
    - King's Daughters receipts, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - King's Daughters receipts, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - King's Daughters receipts, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - King's Daughters receipts, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - King's Daughters membership and dues, 1898 1912; 1898-1912 (Box 3, Volume 10)
    - King's Daughters membership and dues, 1912 1922; 1912-1922 (Box 3, Volume 11)
    - King's Daughters membership and dues, 1922 1946; 1922-1946 (Box 3, Volume 12)
    - King's Daughters membership and dues, 1946 1950; 1946-1950 (Box 3, Volume 13)
    - King's Daughters membership lists, 1957 1967; 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rollstone Circle of King's Daughters records, 1898 1905; 1898-1905 (Box 3, Volume 14)
    - Rollstone Circle of King's Daughters records and historical sketchs, 1916 1938; 1916-1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - United Workers of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1891 1957; 1891-1957; 9 Cubic Feet; (8 volumes, 1 folder)
    This subseries contains the record books of the United Worker's Guild of the C. C. Church, which include minutes, financial records, event programs, and documents about the history of the society.
    - United Workers secretary book, 1891 1902; 1891-1902 (Box 4, Volume 1)
    - United Workers records, 1902 1911; 1902-1911 (Box 4, Volume 2)